[Music]
to meet your financial dreams you need a
strong financial plan it includes
choosing right products for investments
will SBI life smart future choices plan
be one of your right investment choices
this video helps you to find out whether
SBI life smart choices plan is the right
investment choice for your Investment
Portfolio or not welcome to holistic
investment.
SBI life smart future choices plan is a
uh is an individual non-l participating
life insurance savings product in this
video let us look at the features death
benefit maturity benefit IR of this
policy and also let us compare this
policy with other
investment uh first uh let us look at
the features you can stay financially
protected throughout the policy term two
benefit options uh that is uh classic
choice or uh Flex Flexi Choice uh cash
bonuses are available from the end of
the second policy year you can
completely enjoy the flexibility of
choosing your benefit payouts as per
your changing financial needs money on
demand Sur survival benefit payouts
available at defined intervals under the
flexi Choice
option before looking at the benefit
options let us look at the plan option
classic Choice with this option you
enjoy a lum some maturity benefit at the
end of the policy term along with life
cover throughout the policy term next is
flexi choice on opting for flexi Choice
option you will be eligible to get 10%
of your Basics suured as survival
benefit at specified intervals along
with your maturity benefit of 80% of
Basics suured at the end of your policy
term along with life cover throughout
your policy
term benefit options of SBA life smart
future choices plan survival benefit
there are no survival benefit payable
under the classic Choice option under
Choice option you will be eligible to
get two benefit payouts of 10% of Basics
suured each at specified intervals you
can defer one or both survival benefits
and can be taken any time during the
remaining policy term or it will be paid
at the dep of the life assured or
Surrender or on maturity next maturity
benefit on Survival till the end of the
policy term the following will be
payable in lump suum under classic
Choice guaranteed suured on maturity
plus accumulated deferred cash bonus if
any plus terminal bonus if declared
guaranteed suured on maturity will be
based on age premium paying term and
policy term and reflex Choice option
guaranteed Su on maturity plus
accumulated survival benefit if any plus
accumulated deferred cash bonus if any
plus terminal bonus if declared the
guaranteed suured on maturity will be
equal to 80% of basic suured next death
benefit on death of the life assured
during the policy term the following
will be payable higher of some assured
on De Plus accumulated deferred cash
bonus plus terminal bonus or minimum sum
uh minimum death benefit which is equal
to 105% of total premiums received up to
the date of death where some assured on
death is 11 times of annualized Premium
if the policy holder has opted for flexi
Choice then in addition to the above
benefit accumulated survival benefit if
any will also be paid now let us look at
the advantages and disadvantages of SBI
life smart future choices plan
advantages option to choose the premium
paying term and policy term as per your
convenience enjoy the flexibility to
Avail your benefits as per your
financial needs with two benefit option
to choose from you may opt to change
your benefit option later which can be
done after the end of the premium paying
term up to 9 months you have the option
to defer the survival benefit under
flexi Choice option and uh cash bonus
under both option next disadvantages
policy loan is not available the
maturity benefit will not be sufficient
to meet the inflated cost of the
financial goals the sum assured is
inadequate to meet your family's future
financial
needs after analyzing the basic details
of the plan it is not easy to decide
whether to include SBI life a smart
future Choice plan in your Investment
Portfolio or not so let us figure out
the internal rate of return for this
policy this result can be compared with
other investment returns let us assume
that a 35-year old male of opts for this
SBI life smart future Choice plan with
an annual premium of rupees 150,000 he
opts for classic option and defers the
cash bonus as well the summer sh is rup
22 23,000 and the policy term is 20
years and the premium paying term is 15
years the assumed rates of return uh at
4% and 8% per anom respectively are only
illustrative scenarios and assumed
constant during the bonus approval
period whereas actual bonus could vary
these rates of returns are not guarant
aned and they are not higher or lower
limit limit of returns under the assumed
rate of 4% scenario the IR is
2.46% under the assumed rate of 8%
scenario the irr is
4.35% this rate is far
below uh than any debt instrument return
you get a better return by investing in
a bank FD compared to investing in SBA
life smart future choices plan the
return from this SBA life smart future
Cho policy are not sufficient to keep up
with the inflation which can reduce the
real value of the policy payout the life
cover provided is also limited compared
to a pure term insurance policy now let
us find out what would be the returns if
we invest the same amount of R 150,000
in other investment Alternatives SBA
life smart future Choice plan is an
endowment policy so we can utilize the
premium for Life cover and also for
investment yeah P term insurance policy
for a sumers sh of R 25 lakhs would cost
rupes 21,000 the policy term is 20 years
and the premium paying term is 10 years
after the premium after paying the pure
term insurance the balance could be
utilized for investment
purposes in the earlier illustration the
premium paying term is for 15 years but
here for Pure term insurance policy it
is 10 years so in the next 5 years the
whole amount of R 150,000 could be
utilized for investment we have chosen
one debt instrument and one Equity
instrument uh ppf for debt and elss for
equity for our comparison the elss
maturity proceeds are subject to capital
gains tax here we have given taken the
post tax maturity value the elss tax
calculation is given here the irr for
pter insurance along with BPF investment
is 6.24% and the irr for pter insurance
along with elss investment is 10.47%
which is post tax return these number
numers uh add evidence to the point that
investing separately for your life's
financial goals is always the best
choice final verdict on SBI life smart
future choices plan SBI life smart
future Choice plan is a comprehensive
investment come insurance plan that
provides two Benefit Plan option to the
policy holder along with the life cover
the plan also offers flexibility in
terms of Premium paying and policy term
it allows you to defer the cash bonus
after the analysis we would like to
conclude that both from an investment
per perspective and from Life cover
perspective the SBA life smart future
Choice plan will not be beneficial to
you while an endowment policy May
provide a combination of Life cover and
savings benefit it is important to
consider the potential return before
investing in such a policy you can
consult with your financial adviser to
curate the perfect financial plan best
suited to your financial goals to
achieve better results
it is advisable to carefully evaluate
your financial needs and investment
goals before deciding on the best
investment product for you a detailed
blog post on this topic is available in
our website and the link is given in the
description
box hope you like this video if you have
any questions related to this or any
other investment option or related to
your financial goal don't hesitate to
book a free appointment with our
financial planners the link to the free
booking is given in the description box
below also will you be interested to
attend any insightful investment webinar
then feel free to register for the
upcoming enlightening investment webinar
it is completely free the registration
link for the upcoming webinar is also
given in the description box if you like
this video please give us thumbs up also
share it with your Social Circle if you
haven't subscribed our YouTube channel
so far please sub subscribe now